Qurat Ul Ain Fatima

+92 305 6298871

quratfatima581@gmail.com GitHub: @QuratFatima906

LinkedIn: pk.linkedin.com/in/qurat-ul-ain-fatima

Objective:

You open a new browser tab, type in a URL, and press enter. The site loads instantly. It nearly takes your breath away with its ultra-clean layout, well-constructed pages, and impressive user experience. My aim is to create those clean and optimized web applications to make the web a better place to visit.

Education

Front-end Web Developer Nanodegree - 2018

Arbisoft-Udacity Scholarship

Majors: Angular, ReactJS, Ember, Backbone, JavaScript ES6

Masters in Computer Science - 2017 (CGPA 3.32)

Punjab University College of Information Technology, Lahore

Majors: Web Development(.NET), Mobile Computing, Computer Networks,

Enterprise Application Development, Object Oriented Programming, Analysis of Algorithms

Skills & Tools

- Languages: JavaScript ES6, ReactJS, AngularJS, Ember, HTML5, CSS3, JQuery, Bootstrap, ASP.NET(MVC, Web API)
- Version Control: Git
- Testing & Build: Jasmine, Grunt, Gulp
- Design: Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Fireworks, Adobe After Effects

Projects

Neighborhood Map

A **React-Redux** single-page application using **Google Maps** and **Foursquare APIs** to display a map of Lahore, highlighting places to get Libraries. (*ReactJS*)

- My Reads

A **React** application that keeps track of books and helps to manage them into three categories Read, Currently reading, and Want to read. (*ReactJS*, *Bootstrap*)

Feed Reader

A web-based application that reads RSS feeds. Developed to practice Jasmine through 'test-driven' process.

- Arcade Game

Arcade Game is a project to practice **Object Oriented JavaScript**. Player has to cross roadway avoiding enemy bugs while collecting maximum number of gems and lives. (*JavaScript ES6, HTML5, and CSS*)

- **Zotero Citation Manager** (Final Year Project)

Open source citation manager, deployed on the server of PUCIT with extra features of **privacy**, **role management** and **friendly web interface**. (PHP, MySQL, JavaScript, HTML, CSS)

Work Experience

UI/UX & Graphics Designer (September 2017 – August 2018)

Brain Games Studio

While working at Brain Games Studio, I designed educational games. My projects were presented on Momentum Tech Conference 2018.

■ Internship (2016 – 2017)

Artificial Intelligence and Multidisciplinary Research Lab (AIM-RL)

Worked on Linux base server deployment – used GIT and source tree for concurrent management of code and practiced Daily Scrum Meeting (DSM).

Honors & Awards

- Technovation Judge -- 2018
- Poster Design Winner: Mindsweeper 2017 & 2018, Forman Christian College, Lahore
- 77-418: MOS: Microsoft Office Specialist Word 2013 December 2017
- **77-422: MOS**: Microsoft Office Specialist Power Point 2013 -- December 2017
- Principal List Award: Semester 4 -- 2017

Interests

Logo Designing, Creative Writing, Book Reading, Painting, Sketching, Photography, Badminton, and Chess